<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Shilpi Agrawal]]></title><description><![CDATA[Product Management, Randomness, Diary, Logging of stuff]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 14:32:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Why I Avoid Using LinkedIn]]></title><description><![CDATA[Coming Soon. Stay Tuned!]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/linkedin-product-user-pain-points</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/linkedin-product-user-pain-points</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;“Coming Soon. Stay Tuned!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- - [The first transition](#the-first-transition)
- [The digital age](#the-digital-age)
- [Loss of humanity through transitions](#loss-of-humanity-through-transitions)
- [Chasing perfection](#chasing-perfection)

An Essay on Typography by Eric Gill takes the reader back to the year 1930. The year when a conflict between two worlds came to its term. The machines of the industrial world finally took over the handicrafts.

The typography of this industrial age was no longer handcrafted. Mass production and profit became more important. Quantity mattered more than the quality. The books and printed works in general lost a part of its humanity. The typefaces were not produced by craftsmen anymore. It was the machines printing and tying the books together now. The craftsmen had to let go of their craft and became a cog in the process. An extension of the industrial machine.

But the victory of the industrialism didn’t mean that the craftsmen were completely extinct. The two worlds continued to coexist independently. Each recognising the good in the other — the power of industrialism and the humanity of craftsmanship. This was the second transition that would strip typography of a part of its humanity. We have to go 500 years back in time to meet the first one.

## The first transition

A similar conflict emerged after the invention of the first printing press in Europe. Johannes Gutenberg invented movable type and used it to produce different compositions. His workshop could print up to 240 impressions per hour. Until then, the books were being copied by hand. All the books were handwritten and decorated with hand drawn ornaments and figures. A process of copying a book was long but each book, even a copy, was a work of art.

The first printed books were, at first, perceived as inferior to the handwritten ones. They were smaller and cheaper to produce. Movable type provided the printers with flexibility that allowed them to print books in languages other than Latin. Gill describes the transition to industrialism as something that people needed and wanted. Something similar happened after the first printed books emerged. People wanted books in a language they understood and they wanted books they could take with them. They were hungry for knowledge and printed books satisfied this hunger.

![42-line-bible.jpg](/media/42-line-bible.jpg)

*The 42–Line Bible, printed by Gutenberg.*

But, through this transition, the book lost a large part of its humanity. The machine took over most of the process but craftsmanship was still a part of it. The typefaces were cut manually by the first punch cutters. The paper was made by hand. The illustrations and ornaments were still being hand drawn. These were the remains of the craftsmanship that went almost extinct in the times of Eric Gill.

## The digital age

The first transition took away a large part of humanity from written communication. Industrialisation, the second transition described by Eric Gill, took away most of what was left. But it’s the third transition that stripped it naked. Typefaces are faceless these days. They’re just fonts on our computers. Hardly anyone knows their stories. Hardly anyone cares. Flicking through thousands of typefaces and finding the “right one” is a matter of minutes.

&gt; In the new computer age the proliferation of typefaces and type manipulations represents a new level of visual pollution threatening our culture. Out of thousands of typefaces, all we need are a few basic ones, and trash the rest.
&gt;
— Massimo Vignelli

Typography is not about typefaces. It’s not about what looks best, it’s about what feels right. What communicates the message best. Typography, in its essence, is about the message. “Typographical design should perform optically what the speaker creates through voice and gesture of his thoughts.”, as El Lissitzky, a famous Russian typographer, put it.

## Loss of humanity through transitions

Each transition took away a part of humanity from written language. Handwritten books being the most humane form and the digital typefaces being the least. Overuse of Helvetica is a good example. Messages are being told in a typeface just because it’s a safe option. It’s always there. Everyone knows it but yet, nobody knows it. Stop someone on the street and ask him what Helvetica is? Ask a designer the same question. Ask him where it came from, when, why and who designed it. Most of them will fail to answer these questions. Most of them used it in their precious projects but they still don’t spot it in the street.

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of the quality of a typeface is of the greatest importance for the functional, aesthetic and psychological effect.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;footer&gt;
			&lt;cite&gt;— Josef Mueller-Brockmann&lt;/cite&gt;
		&lt;/footer&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

Typefaces don’t look handmade these days. And that’s all right. They don’t have to. Industrialism took that away from them and we’re fine with it. We’ve traded that part of humanity for a process that produces more books that are easier to read. That can’t be bad. And it isn’t.

&gt; Humane typography will often be comparatively rough and even uncouth; but while a certain uncouthness does not seriously matter in humane works, uncouthness has no excuse whatever in the productions of the machine.
&gt;
&gt; — Eric Gill

We’ve come close to “perfection” in the last five centuries. The letters are crisp and without rough edges. We print our compositions with high–precision printers on a high quality, machine made paper.

![type-through-time.jpg](/media/type-through-time.jpg)

*Type through 5 centuries.*

We lost a part of ourselves because of this chase after perfection. We forgot about the craftsmanship along the way. And the worst part is that we don’t care. The transition to the digital age made that clear. We choose typefaces like clueless zombies. There’s no meaning in our work. Type sizes, leading, margins… It’s all just a few clicks or lines of code. The message isn’t important anymore. There’s no more “why” behind the “what”.

## Chasing perfection

Human beings aren’t perfect. Perfection is something that will always elude us. There will always be a small part of humanity in everything we do. No matter how small that part, we should make sure that it transcends the limits of the medium. We have to think about the message first. What typeface should we use and why? Does the typeface match the message and what we want to communicate with it? What will be the leading and why? Will there be more typefaces in our design? On what ground will they be combined? What makes our design unique and why? This is the part of humanity that is left in typography. It might be the last part. Are we really going to give it up?

*Originally published by [Matej Latin](http://matejlatin.co.uk/) on [Medium](https://medium.com/design-notes/humane-typography-in-the-digital-age-9bd5c16199bd?ref=webdesignernews.com#.lygo82z0x).* --&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Auf Wiedersehen, Gurgaon!]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a short personal note I wrote when I moved to Bangalore from Gurgaon. Gurgaon, of course, has always topped the pollution charts but this note summarizes what it meant for me.]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/until-next-time-gurgaon</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/until-next-time-gurgaon</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;!-- &lt;center&gt;&lt;font size =&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt; Written By Shilpi and 
Shaista &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a short personal note I wrote when I moved to Bangalore from Gurgaon. Gurgaon, of course, has always topped the pollution charts but this note summarizes what it meant for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-right&quot; style=&quot;width: 33%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/a3429/moving1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAwAE/8QAFQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAASI0jRFR/8QAGxAAAwACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIDBBITISL/2gAIAQEAAQUCXLMwbh2mOrSO/CAi+R//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQ/9oACAEDAQE/AT//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQ/9oACAECAQE/AT//xAAcEAACAAcAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQECEiExQWH/2gAIAQEABj8CWRzQGqmW2dEf/8QAGRABAQEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITGR/9oACAEBAAE/Iee6JeQF9DsS0dN0lWyD6hmL/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAb/wD/xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEf/aAAgBAwEBPxBH/8QAFxEAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERQf/aAAgBAgEBPxCrSn//xAAcEAEBAAICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAhMUFRYcH/2gAIAQEAAT8QMKBGk4xCJU0HtxTUtdOA+ZTEm+2R7wRJBsecZXoz/9k=&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/8ac56/moving1.webp 240w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/d3be9/moving1.webp 480w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/e46b2/moving1.webp 960w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/f992d/moving1.webp 1440w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/882b9/moving1.webp 1920w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/39c10/moving1.webp 4160w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/09b79/moving1.jpg 240w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/7cc5e/moving1.jpg 480w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/6a068/moving1.jpg 960w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/644c5/moving1.jpg 1440w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/0f98f/moving1.jpg 1920w,
/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/a3429/moving1.jpg 4160w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/1597def5b08326700b75c2118314e682/6a068/moving1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;moving&quot; title=&quot;moving&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;!-- 	&lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;Kyuki badal important hain&quot; - Zakir Khan &lt;figcaption&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;!-- &lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I sit relieved yet relentless with excitement in Spicejet flight’s emergency exit doorway with way too much leg room which I was never aware Spicejet had, I ponder how things change in a few days. In fact, taking the liberty to rewind my memories a little bit more from a few days to a couple of years, I remember I had my flights booked to Bangalore in 2017. I remember always feeling Gurgaon was a 6-month-affair. But you never know and can never tell. The 6 months turned into 2.5 years. When people ask me if I do anything related to mechanical engineering at all, I look back to that day when I decided to not join core in Bangalore. I do not do anything directly related to mechanical engineering but still have an affinity to make “actual” products. When I started at Gurgaon with zero friends, I never imagined I would land up with genuine bunch of folks - I never imagined I would make such close friends after college. Never imagined would transition from 4-sharing PG to a single room. Yet, somehow did. The change in me is tremendous and Gurgaon has been a part of that journey of change. Somehow will miss Gurgaon despite it being the world’s most polluted city and quite frankly full of TDCs.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will miss the wide roads, everything being at max 30 min away, the scorching heat and quivering cold, ability to speak to every Ola/Uber/Swiggy/Zomato/etcetc person, comfort zone due to familiarity of places and people, ability to pack bags and go to Jaipur on my terms and not dictated by when is flight cheaper. Delhi metro, though I didn’t use it as much as I could have. Above all, I will miss the people who made Gurgaon a bearable place for me from start. Can’t be grateful enough to have known the amazing people by coincidence or by destiny. Have a story around each one of them. Stories which has inspired me, stories of maturity, kindness. I wish I had met the people more often when I had the chance. Hope sometime some of our paths will cross again. Till that time, bye bye, Gurgaon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-left&quot; style=&quot;width: 26%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/5ef17/gurgaon-people.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGQAAAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQBAgMF/8QAFQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAavcRok2I//EABoQAAMAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwAEERL/2gAIAQEAAQUCNe1bYID3qreCMZxXDry7/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEEH/2gAIAQIBAT8Bp//EAB8QAAIBAgcAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQIDISIzQWGRof/aAAgBAQAGPwLK2KPTVJqLax5N+z//xAAbEAEAAgMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMUFhkf/aAAgBAQABPyG+RF2xwOAy9RIH1UUOjzyOdxQ5NsQ//9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABCEP//EABgRAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABIRFR/9oACAEDAQE/EIlTVw//xAAYEQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhgf/aAAgBAgEBPxCG6Gn/xAAcEAEAAgIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMUFRYaH/2gAIAQEAAT8QC9QJUMANZitA6TC028A5g33l7PMah9ALoW1Fn2YzRHtWU1Li2van/9k=&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/8ac56/gurgaon-people.webp 240w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/d3be9/gurgaon-people.webp 480w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/e46b2/gurgaon-people.webp 960w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/b2d4b/gurgaon-people.webp 1152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/09b79/gurgaon-people.jpg 240w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/7cc5e/gurgaon-people.jpg 480w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/6a068/gurgaon-people.jpg 960w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/5ef17/gurgaon-people.jpg 1152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/6a068/gurgaon-people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;friends&quot; title=&quot;friends&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;!-- 	&lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;Kyuki badal important hain&quot; - Zakir Khan &lt;figcaption&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-right&quot; style=&quot;width: 26%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/a3429/tossin.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAAAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIDAQT/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABnq8kQFK//8QAGhAAAwEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIDABESMf/aAAgBAQABBQJh2pWQRT65Vcaltyd//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAGhAAAgIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQESFRcf/aAAgBAQAGPwLHC04eym4//8QAGRABAQEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFx/9oACAEBAAE/Ib5EIMpo7G5qm7uX15ka37m2/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAPH//EABcRAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABETH/2gAIAQMBAT8QekR//8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAER/9oACAECAQE/EG1//8QAGxABAQACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFRYYH/2gAIAQEAAT8QvAKaaDH6WdAi9TFIlW1uC8vcD83kyOqRq9+uF0k9z//Z&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/8ac56/tossin.webp 240w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/d3be9/tossin.webp 480w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/e46b2/tossin.webp 960w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/f992d/tossin.webp 1440w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/882b9/tossin.webp 1920w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/39c10/tossin.webp 4160w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/09b79/tossin.jpg 240w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/7cc5e/tossin.jpg 480w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/6a068/tossin.jpg 960w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/644c5/tossin.jpg 1440w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/0f98f/tossin.jpg 1920w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/a3429/tossin.jpg 4160w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/6a068/tossin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;food tossin&quot; title=&quot;food tossin&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;!-- 	&lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;Kyuki badal important hain&quot; - Zakir Khan &lt;figcaption&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-left&quot; style=&quot;width: 26%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/ff5b6/gurgaon-vmock.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 57.91666666666667%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAMABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUBAv/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAHEviL6Cr//xAAbEAABBAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAIDERIUMv/aAAgBAQABBQJs4x2LcJ4yhxaC/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAHBAAAQMFAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQMhEhMVGB/9oACAEBAAY/Aol8aJU4K/8A/8QAGxAAAgIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAASEAETFBcaH/2gAIAQEAAT8heFqOE9S4qKOTBnhGftS13GZn/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABBf3//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQ/9oACAEDAQE/ECf/xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARAAH/2gAIAQIBAT8QWcv/xAAbEAEAAwEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMUFRcf/aAAgBAQABPxChyr7J40Xz7C4dOw8CrT92JVe+r1Ae0IH5PQ2iYujc/9k=&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/8ac56/gurgaon-vmock.webp 240w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/d3be9/gurgaon-vmock.webp 480w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/e46b2/gurgaon-vmock.webp 960w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/c18de/gurgaon-vmock.webp 1052w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/09b79/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 240w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/7cc5e/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 480w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/6a068/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 960w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/ff5b6/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 1052w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/6a068/gurgaon-vmock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;friends&quot; title=&quot;friends&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;!-- 	&lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;Kyuki badal important hain&quot; - Zakir Khan &lt;figcaption&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;    
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;!--   &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;First Screen Page&lt;/td&gt;
     &lt;td&gt;Holiday Mention&lt;/td&gt;
     &lt;td&gt;Present day in purple and selected day in pink&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt; --&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/5ef17/gurgaon-people.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGQAAAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQBAgMF/8QAFQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAavcRok2I//EABoQAAMAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwAEERL/2gAIAQEAAQUCNe1bYID3qreCMZxXDry7/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEEH/2gAIAQIBAT8Bp//EAB8QAAIBAgcAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQIDISIzQWGRof/aAAgBAQAGPwLK2KPTVJqLax5N+z//xAAbEAEAAgMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMUFhkf/aAAgBAQABPyG+RF2xwOAy9RIH1UUOjzyOdxQ5NsQ//9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABCEP//EABgRAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABIRFR/9oACAEDAQE/EIlTVw//xAAYEQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhgf/aAAgBAgEBPxCG6Gn/xAAcEAEAAgIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMUFRYaH/2gAIAQEAAT8QC9QJUMANZitA6TC028A5g33l7PMah9ALoW1Fn2YzRHtWU1Li2van/9k=&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/8ac56/gurgaon-people.webp 240w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/d3be9/gurgaon-people.webp 480w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/e46b2/gurgaon-people.webp 960w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/b2d4b/gurgaon-people.webp 1152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/09b79/gurgaon-people.jpg 240w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/7cc5e/gurgaon-people.jpg 480w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/6a068/gurgaon-people.jpg 960w,
/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/5ef17/gurgaon-people.jpg 1152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/3e58c365d77f181a535ec14ac8392a13/6a068/gurgaon-people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;gurgaon people&quot; title=&quot;gurgaon people&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/a3429/tossin.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAAAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIDAQT/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABnq8kQFK//8QAGhAAAwEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIDABESMf/aAAgBAQABBQJh2pWQRT65Vcaltyd//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAGhAAAgIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQESFRcf/aAAgBAQAGPwLHC04eym4//8QAGRABAQEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFx/9oACAEBAAE/Ib5EIMpo7G5qm7uX15ka37m2/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAPH//EABcRAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABETH/2gAIAQMBAT8QekR//8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAER/9oACAECAQE/EG1//8QAGxABAQACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFRYYH/2gAIAQEAAT8QvAKaaDH6WdAi9TFIlW1uC8vcD83kyOqRq9+uF0k9z//Z&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/8ac56/tossin.webp 240w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/d3be9/tossin.webp 480w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/e46b2/tossin.webp 960w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/f992d/tossin.webp 1440w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/882b9/tossin.webp 1920w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/39c10/tossin.webp 4160w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/09b79/tossin.jpg 240w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/7cc5e/tossin.jpg 480w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/6a068/tossin.jpg 960w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/644c5/tossin.jpg 1440w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/0f98f/tossin.jpg 1920w,
/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/a3429/tossin.jpg 4160w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/01572c7a9810384ae4b50660a52db04e/6a068/tossin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tossin&quot; title=&quot;tossin&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/ff5b6/gurgaon-vmock.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 57.91666666666667%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAMABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUBAv/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAHEviL6Cr//xAAbEAABBAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAIDERIUMv/aAAgBAQABBQJs4x2LcJ4yhxaC/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAHBAAAQMFAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQMhEhMVGB/9oACAEBAAY/Aol8aJU4K/8A/8QAGxAAAgIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAASEAETFBcaH/2gAIAQEAAT8heFqOE9S4qKOTBnhGftS13GZn/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABBf3//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQ/9oACAEDAQE/ECf/xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARAAH/2gAIAQIBAT8QWcv/xAAbEAEAAwEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMUFRcf/aAAgBAQABPxChyr7J40Xz7C4dOw8CrT92JVe+r1Ae0IH5PQ2iYujc/9k=&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/8ac56/gurgaon-vmock.webp 240w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/d3be9/gurgaon-vmock.webp 480w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/e46b2/gurgaon-vmock.webp 960w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/c18de/gurgaon-vmock.webp 1052w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/09b79/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 240w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/7cc5e/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 480w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/6a068/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 960w,
/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/ff5b6/gurgaon-vmock.jpg 1052w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/f2c93221ff6c7352d45385bccca16900/6a068/gurgaon-vmock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;gurgaon vmock&quot; title=&quot;gurgaon vmock&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/shilpi.agrawal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Shilpi Agrawal&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bv6LQeABCiRie-12iN9r0_JJqL2eVBBT-cwagQ0/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who Am I?]]></title><description><![CDATA[A long poem written by Shaista and I depicting the haphazard, clogged, jumbled up internal existential crisis. This poem is an attempt to address overarching dilemmas. It's an attempt to ask the moral, philosophical and ethical questions. A world-full of people moving towards stress and anxiety, the poem asks some ignored questions. I hope our poem reaches some people asking difficult questions in life.]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/who-am-i</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/who-am-i</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;center&gt;&lt;font size =&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt; Written By Shilpi and 
Shaista &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/b99c8/badal.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 44.99999999999999%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAJABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIDBP/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAD/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAG6a40mhsD/xAAaEAACAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAgEQERIz/9oACAEBAAEFAsCpEmlN0P/EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQMBAT8BP//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAR/9oACAECAQE/Aar/xAAYEAEAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABAxUf/aAAgBAQAGPwKPSa0V/8QAGxAAAQQDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQAQIXGBofH/2gAIAQEAAT8hlaABAJlcDajf/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAnD//EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARAf/aAAgBAwEBPxCJj//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAR/9oACAECAQE/EKU//8QAHRABAAICAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQAhETFRYUGx8P/aAAgBAQABPxBa3yy6zzEnuObFVjpjagPAkPcdk+HuGif/2Q==&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/8ac56/badal.webp 240w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/d3be9/badal.webp 480w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/e46b2/badal.webp 960w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/f992d/badal.webp 1440w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/68d4c/badal.webp 1612w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/09b79/badal.jpg 240w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/7cc5e/badal.jpg 480w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/6a068/badal.jpg 960w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/644c5/badal.jpg 1440w,
/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/b99c8/badal.jpg 1612w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/b0068b773cacd491377707e08f286c31/6a068/badal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;badal&quot; title=&quot;badal&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;quot;Kyuki badal important hain&amp;quot; - Zakir Khan &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A long poem written by Shaista and I&lt;/em&gt; depicting the haphazard, clogged, jumbled up internal existential crisis. This poem is an attempt to address overarching dilemmas. It’s an attempt to ask the moral, philosophical and ethical questions. A world-full of people moving towards stress and anxiety, the poem asks some ignored questions. I hope our poem reaches some people asking difficult questions in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I these strings that bind me?&lt;br&gt;
Erasing my dreams that see&lt;br&gt;
But that can’t be for I can be free&lt;br&gt;
Then must I exist in my reverie?    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I my body, my face, my hair?&lt;br&gt;
That is what attracts the most glare&lt;br&gt;
But how can that be me&lt;br&gt;
If I need to look at a mirror to see   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I must be a bit of her or him&lt;br&gt;
For I talk of their interests and them&lt;br&gt;
They built pieces of me like many more&lt;br&gt;
Can i be so many yet have my own core?   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what might be the nature of my core&lt;br&gt;
Does it include my qualities like my quality of wanting more?&lt;br&gt;
Or is my core made of my philosophy, my principles, my morality?&lt;br&gt;
But what exactly are these in reality?&lt;br&gt;
Does there exist an SI unit of someone’s core?&lt;br&gt;
Because in life, I have seen immorable people soar&lt;br&gt;
The truthful, naive moral people others abhor   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But does it matter who they despise?&lt;br&gt;
Why should I ever chastise&lt;br&gt;
Virtues of mine were in my wise&lt;br&gt;
Not a stepping stone for me to rise&lt;br&gt;
Why then should I mourn their superiority?&lt;br&gt;
Is it not my heart’s depravity,&lt;br&gt;
To seek something of my purity&lt;br&gt;
Contradicting to a point of immorality?   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I am the role I play in this world&lt;br&gt;
But isn’t this role just a role which at me life hurled?&lt;br&gt;
If I consider the world a big stage, what role do I anyway play?&lt;br&gt;
Am I just a passer-by to the billion lives or am I gonna stay?&lt;br&gt;
If I zoom out of my city, state, country, continent, planet and see the vast empty space&lt;br&gt;
Does it matter to the space what is my career pace?&lt;br&gt;
What is the reason for my existence?&lt;br&gt;
Is the reason just to ponder over this question with persistence?&lt;br&gt;
Am I just one of the million atoms floating around in the vast universe?&lt;br&gt;
Or am I the money gloating around in my tiny purse?&lt;br&gt;
They say people find soulmates and marry them&lt;br&gt;
They must be seeing my soul before marrying&lt;br&gt;
Then my soul must be defined by the money I am carrying   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I am too small to know&lt;br&gt;
The truth that runs all this show&lt;br&gt;
To keep the glory intact&lt;br&gt;
There are trifles that distract&lt;br&gt;
But how could I know if I fall&lt;br&gt;
A prey to these frivolity’s call   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start by enslaving the master&lt;br&gt;
The mind that controls shall be the prisoner&lt;br&gt;
So that I can break out of the teachings&lt;br&gt;
Because it definitely triggers my musings&lt;br&gt;
Only when I unlearn will I begin to learn&lt;br&gt;
What my notions have kept hidden   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What defines me, I shall set free&lt;br&gt;
Hey me, It’s an open minded quest for thee&lt;br&gt;
Rather than blindly following the norms&lt;br&gt;
Thou shalt question everything in all the forms&lt;br&gt;
Thou shan’t have to follow the conventional cycle of life&lt;br&gt;
Birth, Studies, Job, and then a wife   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of unlearning is more difficult than learning&lt;br&gt;
Sitting idle is more difficult than earning&lt;br&gt;
Squeezing the paste inside is more difficult than taking it out&lt;br&gt;
Being silent is more powerful than your shout&lt;br&gt;
Forgetting something is more difficult than creating memories&lt;br&gt;
Writing a poem is less expensive than a therapist’s fees   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am learning to unlearn what I earlier learnt&lt;br&gt;
Not use the fancy words, I want to be blunt&lt;br&gt;
The existential crisis that has become the common identity&lt;br&gt;
A place where you are judged by your prosperity&lt;br&gt;
Not your perspective but your money matters&lt;br&gt;
Not your morals but your gold chatters&lt;br&gt;
We are a population divided by money but united by existential crisis&lt;br&gt;
Who is it sitting in the sky playing the dices?&lt;br&gt;
My cluttered thoughts are turning a tad bit more into a clutter&lt;br&gt;
They are following the pattern of a naive butterfly’s flutter   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my mind is still a muddle&lt;br&gt;
And I have no answer to life’s puzzle&lt;br&gt;
I’ve learnt to find order in the chaos&lt;br&gt;
Taking each day as the life throws    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gibberish I see is a pattern&lt;br&gt;
Which can only be seen if I leave my dark cavern&lt;br&gt;
If I zoom out for a second and try to see&lt;br&gt;
The beautiful pattern is always smiling at me&lt;br&gt;
The nature has it all figured out&lt;br&gt;
It does the best for us, without a doubt&lt;br&gt;
For sudden turns, everyone curse, blame, cry and everyone clings&lt;br&gt;
Only to later realise the greater scheme of things&lt;br&gt;
You can’t see the design and you whine&lt;br&gt;
You are the ant which sees from the FOV nature assign&lt;br&gt;
But someday you will realise&lt;br&gt;
All your life events are a boon in disguise&lt;br&gt;
All that happens with you, has a purpose and a noble reason&lt;br&gt;
If there is winter, always comes a  spring season   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, is it a validation that I seek from others&lt;br&gt;
Is that why I live, my being shudders&lt;br&gt;
A person telling me that yes, I am insanely good&lt;br&gt;
Isn’t that all we seek in adulthood&lt;br&gt;
Do I just seek an acceptance in this society&lt;br&gt;
A boost to my ego and my vanity&lt;br&gt;
Maybe that is why I do inhuman things- to gel well&lt;br&gt;
Because gel-ing well is more important that skipping hell&lt;br&gt;
Does my whole sense of being revolve around looking cool&lt;br&gt;
If my life is a car, is admiration the only fuel?   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, any interesting analogy of my life being a car!&lt;br&gt;
Fuel stations may sometimes be near and sometimes far&lt;br&gt;
The fuel may be a happy memory, a tiny success, a good conversation&lt;br&gt;
Something which keeps me going till the next station&lt;br&gt;
A constant love amounts a lot&lt;br&gt;
If something feels right, it’s worth a shot&lt;br&gt;
A bumpy ride sometimes till I hit the highway road&lt;br&gt;
Sometimes the fuel might end and I may need to be towed&lt;br&gt;
Sometimes all I require is a small push or kick start acceleration&lt;br&gt;
A push which leads me to my destination&lt;br&gt;
Or maybe just sends me to next station   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mind, you see, is full of chaos&lt;br&gt;
The universe might have said “You want me to increase entropy? - Here goes”&lt;br&gt;
I wonder if the stable mind is better than a chaotic one&lt;br&gt;
I wonder how does the stable one have some fun&lt;br&gt;
Or maybe it is a matter of multiple states of mind&lt;br&gt;
Where it goes through happiness, sadness and rewind   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of reference frame renders the question “Who am I” pointless&lt;br&gt;
Who is supposed to answer - you need to address&lt;br&gt;
For a wife, you are a husband&lt;br&gt;
For a friend, you are a friend&lt;br&gt;
For a daughter, you are a mother&lt;br&gt;
For a sister, you are a brother   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the question is aimed at you, yourself&lt;br&gt;
Its a loop within a loop itself&lt;br&gt;
You can’t say ‘to publish something’ is definition of ‘publication’&lt;br&gt;
You don’t say ‘to converse’ means ‘having a conversation’&lt;br&gt;
I am asking myself that who am I&lt;br&gt;
If I know where my thoughts generate, it will simplify&lt;br&gt;
Where am I actually expecting the answer from is the answer in itself&lt;br&gt;
Which component is answering that within myself&lt;br&gt;
Maybe I am my brain, or maybe I am my mind&lt;br&gt;
Where is this thought originating from is what I need to find&lt;br&gt;
I maybe am my heart, or maybe my conscience&lt;br&gt;
Or maybe I will find out with some advancements in science   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one thing I know for sure is that I am deeper than my skin&lt;br&gt;
A vessel and what’s inside the vessel can not always be akin&lt;br&gt;
Although the structure or material might tell you a lot or might not&lt;br&gt;
It’s definitely not all what a vessel has got&lt;br&gt;
But I wonder why we put all our time to keep the vessel shining&lt;br&gt;
Why not spend more time in thinking and thoughts mining&lt;br&gt;
Maybe because nobody is ready to climb up and peep inside the vessel&lt;br&gt;
As it may be causing a lot of hassle&lt;br&gt;
Every hemisphere requires another one to complete a closed sphere&lt;br&gt;
Maybe being with someone is the law of nature and it’s only fair&lt;br&gt;
I would have left my thoughts to wander more, but I do not dare&lt;br&gt;
In getting distracted, I have a natural flair   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the distraction is the real order and the real order a distraction&lt;br&gt;
Maybe a dream is a reality and reality a dream in action&lt;br&gt;
At this point, I think I should take a bath&lt;br&gt;
To save myself from my mother’s telephonic wrath&lt;br&gt;
Hopefully, I have confused you a lot&lt;br&gt;
You’ll miss me in the 2050 - the world of bot!   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/shilpiagrawal555/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Shilpi Agrawal&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/shilpi-agrawal/who-am-i/2069914386368995&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nirbhaya]]></title><description><![CDATA[A peom written by me telling the story of a young girl. 'Nearly four out of five women in India have faced public harassment ranging from staring, insults and wolf-whistling to being followed, groped or even raped', said a survey by the charity ActionAid UK in 2016. The poem tries to bring a story of one such shattering experience. ]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/nirbhaya</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/nirbhaya</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;center&gt;&lt;font size =&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt; Written By Shilpi &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 960px; &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/0f98f/dark.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAALABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFQABAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAX/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABgCAP/8QAFBABAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIP/aAAgBAQABBQJf/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAFBABAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIP/aAAgBAQAGPwJf/8QAFBABAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIP/aAAgBAQABPyFf/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAIL//EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQMBAT8QP//EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQIBAT8QP//EABQQAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACD/2gAIAQEAAT8QX//Z&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/8ac56/dark.webp 240w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/d3be9/dark.webp 480w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/e46b2/dark.webp 960w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/f992d/dark.webp 1440w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/882b9/dark.webp 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source srcset=&quot;/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/09b79/dark.jpg 240w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/7cc5e/dark.jpg 480w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/6a068/dark.jpg 960w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/644c5/dark.jpg 1440w,
/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/0f98f/dark.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; src=&quot;/static/15b2c152dce6a9437bebbb4724a90ad1/6a068/dark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;darkness&quot; title=&quot;darkness&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Hello darkness, my old friend. &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A peom written by me&lt;/em&gt; telling the story of a young girl. ‘Nearly four out of five women in India have faced public harassment ranging from staring, insults and wolf-whistling to being followed, groped or even raped’, said a survey by the charity ActionAid UK in 2016. The poem tries to bring a story of one such shattering experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to eat panipuri, Mummy”&lt;br&gt;
14-year old said, holding her tummy&lt;br&gt;
“Can we go to that roadside shop?&lt;br&gt;
It’s not even late” she motioned at the clock   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; “I have work to do” her mother said,&lt;br&gt;
“Go by yourself” she added while dusting the bed&lt;br&gt;
“Okay fine, I’ll go by myself” the girl replied&lt;br&gt;
“I am a big girl” she declared with some pride  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  She wore a sweater and left to eat&lt;br&gt;
Panipuri- Something no eatable can beat&lt;br&gt;
She reached the shop and ate&lt;br&gt;
7 o-clock, still not that late  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Just entered her street, she was returning back&lt;br&gt;
Walked some steps and a man on cycle passed, taking her aback&lt;br&gt;
In a flash of second, she just stood there&lt;br&gt;
Trying to understand the air.&lt;br&gt;
It took her a second to solve the quest&lt;br&gt;
Feeling some pain in her left breast&lt;br&gt;
The man had grabbed it tight&lt;br&gt;
She felt herself turning pale white&lt;br&gt;
She managed to turn back in shock&lt;br&gt;
Just to see the man smiling as slowly she walk  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  His cycle disappeared with the turn of road&lt;br&gt;
The only thing on that street now was an ad board&lt;br&gt;
She felt uneasy as tears rolled down&lt;br&gt;
Not knowing what to do, or say, or should she frown?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  She walked as slowly as the teardrops rolled&lt;br&gt;
Reached her home and door she bolt&lt;br&gt;
Her mother asked her what happened, becoming tense&lt;br&gt;
She narrated and her tears turned more intense  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Her mother furiously went on to say&lt;br&gt;
“You should have shouted, should have hold him in the way”&lt;br&gt;
And a hundred condolences and advices&lt;br&gt;
On how to handle such crisis&lt;br&gt;
All she thought was to never go out alone again&lt;br&gt;
But her brain declared that would just be insane  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  In a day, she went back to normal but learned to see&lt;br&gt;
How a person becomes what he/she set out to be  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  There is evil, pain, there is blue&lt;br&gt;
There is evil, pain, there is blue&lt;br&gt;
There are shattering experiences too&lt;br&gt;
One has to emerge out of those a winner&lt;br&gt;
Not to be crushed but some sinner  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  In a country of largest number of rape victims&lt;br&gt;
In a country of poor judiciary systems&lt;br&gt;
You cannot live in fear, you have got to be strong&lt;br&gt;
Sitting in a locked up room would just be wrong.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by Shilpi Agrawal here itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>